RSA involves a public key and a private key. The public key can be known to everyone and is used for encrypting messages. Messages encrypted with the public key can only be decrypted using the private key. The keys for the RSA algorithm are generated the following way:

   1. Choose two distinct prime numbers p and q.
          * For security purposes, the integers p and q should be chosen at random, and should be of similar bit-length. Prime integers can be efficiently found using a primality test.
   2. Compute n = pq.
          * n is used as the modulus for both the public and private keys
   3. Compute f(n) = (p –  1)(q – 1), where f() is Euler's totient function.
   4. Choose an integer e such that 1 < e < f(n) and gcd(e,f(n)) = 1, i.e. e and f(n) are coprime.
          * e is released as the public key exponent.
   5. Determine d = e–1 mod f(n); i.e. d is the multiplicative inverse of e mod f(n).
         

The public key consists of the modulus n and the public (or encryption) exponent e. 
The private key consists of the private (or decryption) exponent d which must be kept secret.